#### Contact

bishttarun2002@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tarun-bisht-38724b201 (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

C (Programming Language)

C++

Python (Programming Language)

### Languages

English (Limited Working)
Punjabi (Full Professional)
Hindi (Full Professional)

### Certifications

Beginner Course on Data Science
Machine Learning Foundations
Workshop on Substance/Drug Abuse
Introduction to Programming Using
HTML and CSS
Command Line

#### Honors-Awards

Cricket
Academics

Biodiversity

# Tarun Bisht

3#Hacker Rank || Defense Aspirant || Member at HTS, GDG, Mozilla Chandigarh, Innovator's Hub || Campus Ambassador at IMUN, Shape AI, ISP 21 || GSSoC'21

Chandigarh

# Summary

# "Simplicity is about subtracting the obvious and adding the meaningful." #

Hey there! This is Tarun Bisht, a computer science engineering student in CU, Punjab. I have some experience in market analysis with software development and making projects which are fully based on AI and ML. I basically aim to innovate new things with some interesting content.

As a undergrad engineer I am trying to learn skills with respect to my field. And what I might lack in skills I make up for with my determination to learn.

In the next few decades, India will rise in technology advancement of quantum computing so as a beginner I want to see my future in quantum physics which gives a different look to our society and even change the lifestyles of the people.

Outside of tech, I am a cricketer, a singer and love to spent my spare time in watching movies.

## Experience

GirlScript Summer of Code Participant February 2021 - Present (2 months) Chandigarh, India

- -GirlScript Summer of Code is the 3 month long Open Source program during summers conducted by GirlScript Foundation, started in 2018.
- -It is started with an aim to help beginners get started with Open Source Development while encouraging diversity.
- -Throughout the program, participants contribute to different projects under guidance of experienced mentors.

Internshala

Campus Ambassador

February 2021 - Present (2 months)

Gurugram, Haryana, India

- -Internshala is an internship and online training platform, based in Gurgaon, India.
- -We are a technology company on a mission to equip students with relevant skills & practical exposure through internships and online trainings.
- -A world where you graduate fully assured, fully confident, and fully prepared to stake a claim on your place in the world.

International MUN

Official Campus Ambasssador

January 2021 - Present (3 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

- -International MUN brings youth together from around the world to learn and share ideas from a diverse set of experiences and backgrounds in its offline & online Model United Nations conferences.
- -International MUN is recognized by the United Nations & has hosted MUN conferences in 5 different countries in the last 3 years i.e in Thailand, Vietnam, Egypt, China & Malaysia.
- -Next IMUN conferences in 2021 are scheduled in the Philippines, Indonesia, South Korea and in other SEA countries.

Hackoverflow Technical Society Committee Member January 2021 - Present (3 months)

Chandigarh, India

- -Hackoverflow Technical Society is the Official Technical Society of Chandigarh University.
- -This society is popularly known for its annual national level hackathon "Hackoverflow".
- -They have organized 3 editions of this national level on-site Hackathon.
- -Hackoverflow Hackathon counts in India's one of the biggest student organized Hackathons.

GDG Chandigarh Volunteer January 2021 - Present (3 months) Chandigarh, India

- -Google Developers Group Chandigarh is an initiative to concentrate the efforts of many developers in and around Chandigarh to learn, share, and get productive using the various Google products.
- -Developer Student Clubs are university based community groups for students interested in Google developer technologies.
- -Students from all undergraduate or graduate programs with an interest in growing as a developer are welcome.
- -By joining a DSC, students grow their knowledge in a peer-to-peer learning environment and build solutions for local businesses and their community.

Mozilla Chandigarh Committee Member January 2021 - Present (3 months) Chandigarh, India

- -At Mozilla, we're a global community of technologists, thinkers and builders working together to keep the Internet alive and accessible, so people worldwide can be informed contributors and creators of the Web.
- -Our mission is to ensure the Internet is a global public resource, open and accessible to all. An Internet that truly puts people first, where individuals can shape their own experience and are empowered, safe and independent.
- -We believe that students are uniquely positioned to make a difference in the world and that by bringing together local groups who care about the internet we can achieve great things.

# ShapeAl Campus Influencer February 2021 - Present (2 months)

Chandigarh, India

- -Shapes AI enables machines to reason with what they see.
- -Shapes Al enables machines to reason with what they see. Our award-winning 'Deep Visual Reasoning' technology analyses scenes to automatically flag pertinent activities and behaviours.
- -With this unprecedented AI capability, we're shaping the future of video analytics.

Innovator's Hub Official Member January 2021 - Present (3 months) Chandigarh, India

- -Innovators hub is a species of brains who work on concepts, ideas and projects which are capable of changing the quotidian of people.
- -We believe that every idea is significant. We don't want a billion dollar idea but an idea that can help billion people. We at Innovators Hub take care of your ideas and help them develop.
- -These hubs serve as springboards for new ideas and innovation and thus helping the society and economy to face future challenges and meet rising aspirations of the growing population.

### Education

#### CHANDIGARH UNIVERSITY

Bachelor of Engineering - BE(Hons.), Computer Science In BIG DATA AND ANALYTICS  $\cdot$  (2020 - 2024)

Govt.Model.Senior.Secondary.School, Sector -19 C Chandigarh High School, CBSE 12th Science-90% · (2018 - 2020)

Govt.Model.Senior.Secondary.School, MHC Chandigarh CBSE 6th-10th (10 CGPA) · (2013 - 2018)